Rolling hills and endless green pastures – those images are easy to conjure when thinking of the idyllic country lifestyle.
连绵起伏的山丘、一望无际的青青牧场——一想到田园诗般的乡村生活，这些画面便会油然而生。
When lockdowns descended upon many countries across the world during the pandemic, social media seemed to be dominated by pictures of cottages and village life – people getting away from it all.
疫情期间，当世界上许多国家开始实施封锁政策时，社交媒体上便被乡村小屋和田园生活的照片刷屏——人们都想逃离喧嚣，寻一处宁静之地。
So, why is living in the countryside becoming a modern fantasy – and are there benefits to considering a slower pace of life?
那么，为什么居住在乡村会成为一种现代憧憬？选择放慢生活节奏又是否真的有益呢？
It makes sense that some people would want to give up the crowded and noisy city streets for the perceived tranquillity of the traditional country life – especially during an event like a pandemic.
不难理解，有些人愿意告别拥挤嘈杂的城市街道，去追寻传统乡村生活中那份印象中的宁静，尤其是在疫情这样的特殊时期。
The lockdowns and extensive periods of working from home have given people time to think about what they want from life.
封锁政策和长时间的居家办公，让人们得以静下心来思考自己真正想要的生活。
But it’s not just about having a greener place to look at out your window.
但这种向往，绝不仅仅是为了能在窗边看到一片更绿意盎然的景色。
There is more evidence that relates to the benefits of rural living.
有更多证据表明乡村生活益处良多。
Villages aren’t normally subject to the stop-go traffic we see in city centres, the buses fighting with taxis for dominance, or metro systems with trains that scream from one station to the next.
乡村通常不会出现市中心那种走走停停的拥堵车流，不会有公交车和出租车抢道争行的混乱场面，也不会有地铁列车呼啸着穿梭于各个站点的嘈杂。
In short, there’s less air pollution in your country retreat – a thing which increases the chances of developing respiratory conditions or heart disease.
简而言之，你的乡村居所空气污染更少——而空气污染恰恰会增加人们患上呼吸系统疾病或心脏病的风险。
You also get more opportunities to take long walks and see the sights, meaning you can get more exercise.
你还能有更多机会漫步赏景，这意味着可以获得更多的运动量。
Less noise, more walks and better air can also lead to less stress and an increased life expectancy, according to studies such as one conducted by the British government in 2012.
英国政府2012年开展的一项研究等相关调查显示，更少的噪音、更多的散步机会以及更优质的空气，还能有效减轻压力，延长人的预期寿命。
However, there are some things that need to be considered.
不过，也有一些问题需要考虑。
Living far from the hustle and bustle of the city means that some people may feel isolated or even lonely.
远离城市的喧嚣意味着有些人可能会感到与世隔绝，甚至产生孤独感。
And as people get older, life far from doctors or public transport could become a bit of a challenge.
而且随着人们年龄增长，居住在远离医生和公共交通的地方，生活可能会变得有些艰难。
So, if you’re considering a change of pace and moving to a picturesque village, there is a range of pros and cons to consider before taking the plunge.
所以，如果你正考虑改变生活节奏，搬到风景如画的乡村居住，那么在仓促决定之前，一定要权衡好其中的利弊。